Supply and demand are like an invisible tug of war that happens whenever we want to buy something
Imagine you're at a carnival and there's a stall with a single
super cool superhero toy left
Lots of children
like you and your friends
would want it
right? This is high demand
But since there's only one toy
it's a limited supply
so this tug of war between wanting the toy and having only one makes it more special and sometimes
more pricey! Now
say there are lots and lots of superhero toys
scattered everywhere
You can simply pick one whenever you want
This is high supply
But because it's so easy to get one
maybe you and your friends don't want a toy that badly
This is low demand
So
when there are too many toys
but not enough kids wanting them
these toys may become cheaper! This amazing invisible game of tug of war
where too much or too little can change how much something costs or how special it is
is what we call supply and demand
Like how toys at the carnival can become more or less expensive or popular
supply and demand shape the prices of all things in our world
from candies to houses!