Imagine you're playing with your toy cars
and you made a long
straight road with your building blocks where your cars will race
But let's say you only have a small magnifying glass to look at them
so you can only see a few of your cars at once
Think of this magnifying glass as a "window"
that you slide along the straight road (the "array" or "list") to view different sets of cars (or "subarrays")
This is what we call the sliding window concept
In computing and mathematics
it's a way of looking at a larger problem - like the whole row of cars - in smaller
more manageable chunks - like the few cars you can see through your magnifying glass
You move the window from one end of the row to the other
while keeping the size of the window constant
meaning you're always looking at the same number of cars
just different ones as you move along the road
Want to know which of your cars are the fastest
or how many red cars are in your collection? The sliding window can help to figure this out by examining all the cars in a simplified
orderly way
It’s like a pair of roving eyes moving across your car race!